华纳兄弟影业
DC漫画
蝙蝠侠:侠影之谜
瑞秋 给我看
Rachel, let me see.
- 借我看看 - 谁找到就是谁的 这是我找到的
-Can l see? -Finders keepers. And l found it.
这是我家的花园
ln my garden.
谁找到就是谁的
Finders keepers.
布鲁斯?
Bruce?
布鲁斯!
妈! 阿尔弗雷德!
Mom! Mr. Alfred!
你又在做梦吗?
Did you have dream?
可怕的恶梦
Nightmare.
比这地方更可怕?
Worse than this place?
他们要跟你干架
They are going to fight you.
- 又要干架? - 不打死你绝不罢休
-Again? -Until they kill you.
那就在吃早餐前打死我吧
Can they kill me before breakfast?
臭小子 你活在地狱
You are in hell, little man.
而我就是魔王
And l am the devil.
你不是魔王
You're not the devil.
你是我的沙包
You're practice.
关到禁闭室
Solitary.
- 为什么? - 为了保护
-Why? -For protection.
- 我才不需要保护 - 保护他们不被你打死
-l don't need protection. -Protection for them.
进去
Get in.
你这么想打击罪犯...
Are you so desperate to fight criminals...
不惜入狱和他们单挑?
...that you lock yourself in to take them on one at a time?
其实我一共有七个对手
Actually, there were seven of them.
我只算到有六个 韦恩先生
l counted six, Mr. Wayne.
你怎么知道我的名字?
How do you know my name?
布鲁斯韦恩仍是个大人物
The world is too small for someone like Bruce Wayne to disappear...
不管你有多么落魄潦倒
...no matter how deep he chooses to sink.
你是谁?
Who are you?
敝姓杜卡 我是忍者大师的代言人
My name is merely Ducard, but l speak for Ra's al Ghul...
他是犯罪集团的克星
...a man greatly feared by the criminal underworld.
他可以指引你一条明路
A man who can offer you a path.
你凭什么认为我需要指引?
What makes you think l need a path?
你这种人是自愿来这种地方
Someone like you is only here by choice.
你想深入了解罪犯的世界
You have been exploring the criminal fraternity...
不管你的目的是什么
...but whatever your original intentions...
你已经迷失了方向
...you have become truly lost.
忍者大师能指引我走哪条路?
And what path can Ra's al Ghul offer?
你和他一样痛恨邪恶力量
The path of a man who shares his hatred of evil...
你也希望能伸张正义
...and wishes to serve true justice.
也就是影武者联盟之路
The path of the League of Shadows.
- 你们是以暴制暴的私刑者 - 并不是
-You're vigilantes. -No, no, no.
在你争我夺之中失利的人 才会变成以暴制暴的私刑者
A vigilante is just a man lost in the scramble for his own gratification.
他们会被击毁或遭囚禁
He can be destroyed or locked up.
但是...如果你能够超越自我极限
But if you make yourself more than just a man...
为一个崇高理想全心投入
...if you devote yourself to an ideal...
他们就无法阻止你
...and if they can't stop you...
你也将成为另一种人
...then you become something else entirely.
什么人?
Which is?
传奇英雄 韦恩先生
Legend, Mr. Wayne.
明天你将被释放
Tomorrow, you will be released.
如果你想打击更凶狠的罪犯
lf you are bored of brawling with thieves and want to achieve something...
东边的山坡有一种罕见的蓝花
...there is a rare blue flower that grows on the eastern slopes.
摘下一朵蓝花
Pick one of these flowers.
如果你能把它带到山巅
lf you can carry it to the top of the mountain...
也许就能找到你当初在寻找的东西
...you may find what you were looking for in the first place.
我在寻找什么?
And what was l looking for?
只有你自己知道
Only you can know that.
回去 你一定要回头
You turn back. You go back.
忍者大师?
Ra's al Ghul?
且慢
Wait.
你在寻找什么?
What are you seeking?
我在寻找...
l seek...
打击犯罪、伸张正义的方法
...the means to fight injustice.
让制造恐惧的恶徒...
To turn fear...
心生恐惧
...against those who prey on the fearful.
你要让别人心生恐惧
To manipulate the fears in others...
就必须先战胜自己内心的恐惧
...you must first master your own.
你准备开战了吗?
Are you ready to begin?
我连站都站不起来
l can.... l can barely stand.
死神不会等你准备好
Death does not wait for you to be ready!
死神绝不手下留情!
Death is not considerate or fair!
你面对死神吧 不容有失
And make no mistake, here you face death.
虎爪
Tiger.
柔术
Jujitsu.
豹掌
Panther.
身手不错 但这不是儿戏
You're skilled. But this is not a dance.
而且你仍然害怕
And you are afraid.
但不是怕我
But not of me.
告诉我 韦恩先生
Tell us, Mr. Wayne...
你害怕什么?
...what do you fear?
布鲁斯?
Bruce?
没事了 没事了
lt's okay. lt's okay.
你不会有事的
You'll be okay.
老爷 我要叫救护车吗?
Will we be needing an ambulance, Master Wayne?
我先替他接骨 待会再照X光
No, l'll set the bone and take him for an x-ray later.
好的 老爷
Very good, sir.
- 对不起 老爷 - 别担心 他没事
-l'm very sorry, sir. l've told... -Don't worry. lt's fine.
你跌得很惨 对吧 少爷?
Took quite a fall, didn't we, Master Bruce?
我们为什么跌倒 布鲁斯?
And why do we fall, Bruce?
这样才能学会站起来
So we can learn to pick ourselves up.
只是小跌了一下 轻微骨折而已
Just a little fall. lt's just a small fracture.
你又想到那些蝙蝠?
The bats again?
你知道他们为什么攻击你吗?
You know why they attacked you, don't you?
- 因为他们怕你 - 他们怕我?
-They were afraid of you. -Afraid of me?
每种生物都有恐惧
All creatures feel fear.
就连可怕的怪物也有?
Even the scary ones?
尤其是可怕的怪物
Especially the scary ones.
我给你看样东西
l got something to show you.
- 你想你妈会喜欢吗? - 当然会
-You think your mother will like them? -Yeah.
- 你该起床了吧? - 好啦
-l think it's time to get up. -Maybe.
不准赖床
No going back to bed.
爸 高架铁路是你盖的吗?
Did you build this train, Dad?
高谭市对韦恩家族很好 但这城市日渐没落
Gotham's been good to our family, but the city's been suffering.
小老百姓的日子过得很辛苦
People less fortunate than us have been enduring very hard times.
于是我们建造经济的大众交通工具 把全体市民连结在一起
So we built a new, cheap, public transportation system to unite the city.
正中央就是...
And at the center...
韦恩大楼
...Wayne Tower.
- 你在那里上班吗? - 不 我在医院工作
-ls that where you work? -No, l work at the hospital.
我把公司交给更好的人管理
l leave the running of our company to much better men.
- 比你更好的人? - 嗯...
-Better? -Well...
比我对做生意更有兴趣的人
...more interested men.
我们可以走吗?
Can we go?
拜托
Please.
好 我们走吧
Okay. Let's go.
- 布鲁斯 你怎么了? - 不是他 是我
-What's wrong, Bruce? -No, no. lt was me.
是我想要出来透透气
l just needed some fresh air.
歌剧听久了很累人 对吧?
A little bit of opera goes a long way. Right, Bruce?
我们回家吧
Come on. Let's go.
皮夹和珠宝 快点
Wallets, jewelry. Come on, fast.
- 没问题 - 快点
-That's fine. -Fast.
别紧张
Take it easy.
别冲动
拿去吧
Here you go.
没关系 没关系
lt's fine. lt's fine.
把皮夹拿去 放过我们
Now just take it and go.
- 我要那串珍珠项链 - 喂...
-l said, jewelry. -Hey...
汤犸斯!
Thomas!
布鲁斯
Bruce.
没关系
lt's okay.
不要害怕
Don't be afraid.
那是你父亲的大衣吗?
ls this your father's?
没关系
lt's okay.
过来
Come here.
穿好了
There you go.
没事了
lt's okay.
戈登
Gordon.
嘿
Hey.
好消息
Good news.
我们逮到凶手了
We got him, son.
你什么都不用操心
You're in excellent hands.
我们会好好打理公司
We'll be watching the empire.
等你长大了再让你接管
When you grow up, it'll be waiting for you.
我替你准备了晚餐
l thought l might prepare a little supper.
- 好吧 - 阿尔弗雷德?
-Very well. -Alfred?
- 是 布鲁斯少爷 - 都是我的错
-Yes, Master Bruce? -lt was my fault, Alfred.
- 我叫他们离开的 - 不是
-l made them leave the theater. -No.
- 要是我不害怕... - 这不是你的错
-lf l hadn't gotten scared.... -lt was nothing that you did.
是凶手一个人的错
lt was him, and him alone.
明白吗?
Do you understand?
我想念他们 我好想念他们
l miss them, Alfred. l miss them so much.
我也是 布鲁斯少爷
So do l, Master Bruce.
我也是
So do l.
你还是认为是你害死你父母的吗?
And do you still feel responsible for your parents' death?
我的愤怒比罪恶感更多
My anger outweighs my guilt.
来吧
Come.
你学会了用愤怒代替罪恶感
You have learned to bury your guilt with anger.
我会教你接受它并面对事实
l will teach you to confront it and to face the truth.
你可以一个人对付六个人 我要教你一个人对付六百人
You know how to fight six men. We can teach you how to engage 600.
你知道怎么把自己藏起来 我可以教你怎么隐形
You know how to disappear. We can teach you to become truly invisible.
隐形?
lnvisible?
小卫
忍者的隐形术全是靠耐心 和矫捷的身手
The ninja understands that invisibility is a matter of patience and agility.
耳听四面、眼观八方
Always mind your surroundings.
忍者会运用火药
Ninjitsu employs explosive powders.
- 做为武器? - 或是障眼法
-As weapons? -Or distractions.
戏剧效果和障眼法很有效
Theatricality and deception are powerful agents.
你不能让敌人把你当成凡人
You must become more than just a man in the mind of your opponent.
- 他是谁? - 一个农夫
-Who is he? -He was a farmer.
他为了抢邻居的农地杀人
Then he tried to take his neighbor's land and became a murderer.
- 现在变成一名囚犯 - 他会有什么下场?
-Now he is a prisoner. -What'll happen to him?
杀人就要偿命 不能姑息养奸
Justice. Crime cannot be tolerated.
社会漠不关心才会让治安败坏
Criminals thrive on the indulgence of society's understanding.
你父母的死不是你的错
Your parents' death was not your fault.
是你父亲的错
lt was your father's.
你不能改变他不敢反击的事实
Anger does not change the fact that your father failed to act.
- 对方的手上有枪 - 那能阻止你吗?
-The man had a gun. -Would that stop you?
我接受过武术训练
l've had training.
那不是重点
The training is nothing!
决心才重要
Will is everything!
主动出击的决心
The will to act.
投降吧
Yield.
你并没有打败我
You haven't beaten me.
你为了杀敌失去重心
You have sacrificed sure footing for a killing stroke.
用力磨擦胸口
Rub your chest.
你的手可以帮你取暖
Your arms will take care of themselves.
你比你父亲更坚强
You are stronger than your father.
你不了解我父亲
You didn't know my father.
我了解你内心的愤怒
But l know the rage that drives you.
你的愤怒让你暂时忘却伤痛 直到你无法承受
That impossible anger strangling the grief, until the memory of your loved one is just...
对亲人的思念
...poison in your veins.
有一天你会希望他们不存在
And one day, you catch yourself wishing the person you loved had never existed...
好让你的痛苦消失
...so you'd be spared your pain.
我并不是一直都住在山上
l wasn't always here in the mountains.
我也有过一个妻子
Once, l had a wife.
我一生的最爱
My great love.
她惨遭杀害
She was taken from me.
我和你一样学会不能纵容坏人
Like you, l was forced to learn there are those without decency...
对他们绝对不能手下留情
...who must be fought without hesitation, without pity.
愤怒给了你很大的力量
Your anger gives you great power.
但若不学会控制 它会毁了你
But if you let it, it will destroy you...
愤怒差点毁了我一生
...as it almost did me.
- 你是如何平息怒气? - 报仇
-What stopped it? -Vengeance.
这对我没有用
That's no help to me.
为什么?
Why, Bruce?
你为什么不为父母报仇?
Why could you not avenge your parents?
听证会后你要回普林斯顿大学
Will you be heading back to Princeton after the hearing, sir...
还是你愿意多留一、两天?
...or can l persuade you to stay on for a day or two?
我不要回去
l'm not heading back at all.
- 你不喜欢那里? - 我很喜欢
-You don't like it there? -l like it fine.
只是校方不喜欢我
They just don't feel the same way.
- 我安排你睡在主卧室 - 不用
-l've prepared the master bedroom. -No.
我睡我的房间就行
My room will be fine.
恕我直言 韦恩宅邸是你的
With all due respect, sir, Wayne Manor is your house.
不 这是我父亲的
No, Alfred, it's my father's house.
- 你父亲过世了 少爷 - 这地方是他的陵墓
-Your father is dead. -This place is a mausoleum.
我宁愿把它的一砖一瓦拆掉
lf l have my way, l'll pull the damn thing down brick by brick.
这是韦恩家族世代相传的宅邸
This house, Master Wayne, has sheltered six generations of your family.
你干嘛在乎? 这又不是你家
Why do you give a damn, Alfred? lt's not your family.
我之所以在乎是因为一位好人...
l give a damn because a good man once made me responsible...
把他心爱的独子
...for what was most precious to him...
托付给我
...in the whole world.
道斯小姐要载你到法院
Miss Dawes has offered to drive you to the hearing.
她大概想劝你不要去
She probably hopes to talk you out of going.
我应该把过去也埋在地下吗?
Should l just bury the past out there with my parents, Alfred?
我不能告诉你该如何面对过去
l wouldn't presume to tell you what to do with your past, sir.
但是有很多人关心你的未来
Just know that there are those of us who care about what you do with your future.
你还没放弃我 是吗?
Haven't given up on me yet?
永远都不会
Never.
阿尔弗雷德一向都把炼奶放在最上面
Alfred still keeps the condensed milk on the top shelf.
- 他不知道你已长高、拿得到了吗? - 我猜那是老习惯吧
- Hasn't he noticed you're tall enough to reach now? - Old habits die hard, l guess.
- 我们小时候一样有办法拿到 - 没错
-Never used to stop us anyway. -No, it didn't.
你母亲好吗?
How's your mom?
她很怀念这地方
She misses this place.
我也一样
So do l.
是啊
Yeah.
只可惜现在已经人事全非了
But it's nothing without the people who made it what it was.
- 只有阿尔弗雷德还在这里 - 还有你呀
-Now there's only Alfred. -And you.
- 我不会留下来 瑞秋 - 你只是回来参加听证会
-l'm not staying, Rachel. -You're just back for the hearing.
我知道谁也无法阻止你去
Bruce, l don't suppose there's any way to convince you not to come.
这场听证会总得有人...
Someone at this proceeding...
代表我父母出席
...should stand for my parents.
我们都很爱你的父母
We all loved your parents, Bruce.
- 凶手齐利的行为不可原谅 - 但是你的上司却要让他出狱
-What Chill did is unforgivable. -Then why is your boss letting him go?
他和卡曼费康尼是牢友
ln prison, he shared a cell with Carmine Falcone.
他愿意出庭作证交换提前假释
He learned things, and he will testify in exchange for early parole.
瑞秋 他杀死我父母
Rachel, this man killed my parents.
我不能忘记这件事
l cannot let that pass.
我希望你能了解我的心情
And l need you to understand that, please.
好吧
Okay.
经济大萧条害齐利先生走投无路
The depression hit working people, like Mr. Chill, hardest of all.
虽然他的罪行令人发指 但他是走投无路才铤而走险
His crime was appalling, yes, but it was motivated not by greed, but by desperation.
他已服刑14年 并将协助我们
Given the 1 4 years served, as well as his extraordinary level of cooperation...
侦办地检署最重大的案件
...with one of this office's most important investigations...
因此我们要求让他假释出狱
...we strongly endorse his petition for early release.
齐利先生?
Mr. Chill?
法官大人
Your Honor...
我每天都为我做的事深感悔恨
...not a day goes by that l don't wish l could take back what l did.
我当时的确是走投无路
Sure, l was desperate, like a lot of people back then...
但这不能改变我的所作所为
...but that don't change what l did.
今天有一位韦恩家族成员在场
l gather there is a member of the Wayne family here today.
他有话要说吗?
Has he got anything to say?
- 他从侧门出来了 - 他从侧门出来了 各位!
-He's coming out the side! -He's coming out the side, guys!
- 他来了 - 他来了
布鲁斯韦恩
Bruce Wayne!
乔 乔!
Joe! Hey, Joe!
费康尼老大向你问好
Falcone says hi.
走吧 布鲁斯
Come on, Bruce.
我们不必看到这一幕
We don't need to see this.
我要看
l do.
法官坚持要举行公开听证会
The DA couldn't understand why Judge Faden insisted on making the hearing public.
他一定是被费康尼老大收买了 让齐利公开露面
Falcone paid him off to get Chill out in the open.
也许我应该感谢他们才对
Maybe l should thank them.
- 你不是说真的 - 也许我是说真的 瑞秋
-You don't mean that. -What if l do, Rachel?
是该为我父母伸张正义
My parents deserved justice.
这不是伸张正义而是报仇雪恨
You're not talking about justice. You're talking about revenge.
- 有时候这两者是一样的 - 不 绝对不一样
-Sometimes, they're the same. -No, they're never the same.
伸张正义是为了维持社会和谐 报仇只是为了逞一时之快
Justice is about harmony. Revenge is about you making yourself feel better.
- 所以才会有公正的司法制度 - 司法制度早已名存实亡
-Which is why we have an impartial system. -Your system is broken.
你想伸张正义就要忘却伤痛
You care about justice? Look beyond your own pain, Bruce.
这个城市已经沉沦腐败
This city is rotting.
他们说经济大萧条已成历史 才怪
They talk about the depression as if it's history. lt's not.
老百姓的日子越来越苦
Things are worse than ever here.
黑帮老大费康尼趁火打劫、无恶不作
Falcone floods our streets with crime and drugs...
逼人走上不归路 满街都是齐利之辈
...preying on the desperate, creating new Joe Chills every day.
他也许没有亲手杀死你父母
Falcone may not have killed your parents, Bruce...
却毁了他们代表的一切
...but he's destroying everything that they stood for.
你想感谢他就去吧
You wanna thank him for that? Here you go.
大家都知道他在哪里
We all know where to find him.
但是只要他继续为非作歹 就没有人动得了他
As long as he keeps the bad people rich and the good people scared, no one'll touch him.
你父母这种仗义执言的好人 找不到了
Good people like your parents, who'll stand against injustice, they're gone.
没人挺身而出 高谭市就完了
What chance does Gotham have when the good people do nothing?
- 我不是你说的好人 - 什么意思?
-l'm not one of your good people, Rachel. -What do you mean?
这些年来我一直想杀他 现在没机会了
All these years, l wanted to kill him. Now l can't.
你父亲会以你为耻
Your father would be ashamed of you.
你本人看来比报上的照片高大
You're taller than you look in the tabloids, Mr. Wayne.
你没带枪? 真瞧不起人
No gun? l'm insulted.
- 你大可以寄张感谢卡给我就好 - 我不是来感谢你的
-You could've just sent a thank-you note. -l didn't come here to thank you.
我要告诉你并不是人人都怕你
l came to show you that not everyone in Gotham's afraid of you.
认识我的人才怕我
Only those who know me, kid.
你自己看 这里有两位市议员
Look around you. You'll see two councilmen...
一位工会代表 两名警察
...a union official, couple off-duty cops...
和一位法官
...and a judge.
我大可以在他们面前毙了你
Now, l wouldn't have a second's hesitation of blowing your head off in front of them.
这种权力是买不到的
Now, that's power you can't buy.
这就是恐惧的力量
That's the power of fear.
我并不怕你
l'm not afraid of you.
你自以为能完全豁出去
Because you think you got nothing to lose.
但是你没有想清楚
But you haven't thought it through.
你没想到在地检署工作 青梅竹马的女朋友
You haven't thought about your lady friend in the DA's office.
还有对你忠心耿耿的老管家
You haven't thought about your old butler.
像你这种人
People from your world...
有太多牵挂了
...have so much to lose.
你以为你爹娘被人一枪打死
Now, you think because your mommy and your daddy got shot...
就能了解人性的丑陋吗?
...you know about the ugly side of life, but you don't.
你根本就不知道民间疾苦
You've never tasted desperate.
你是高谭市的天之骄子
You're.... You're Bruce Wayne, the prince of Gotham.
你的大名无人不知、无人不晓
You'd have to go 1 000 miles to meet someone who didn't know your name.
别正气凛然地跑来当一个大英雄
So don't come down here with your anger, trying to prove something to yourself.
你完全不了解犯罪世界
This is a world you'll never understand.
你不了解的事
And you always fear...
永远会让你害怕
...what you don't understand.
动手吧
All right.
我倒是很佩服你的胆识
Yeah, you got spirit, kid. l'll give you that.
你比你老子更带种
More than your old man anyway.
齐利在牢里跟我提到你父母
ln the joint, Chill told me about the night he killed your parents.
他说你老爸向他...
He said your father begged for mercy.
跪地求饶
Begged.
像条狗一样哀号
Like a dog.
你一定是小费给太少了
Should've tipped better.
- 你要什么? - 你的外套
-For what? -Your jacket.
好吧
Okay.
给我吧 这件大衣不错
Hey, hey, hey. Let me have it. lt's a nice coat.
别被人看到你穿这件大衣
Be careful who sees you with that.
- 他们会来找我 - 谁?
-They're gonna come looking for me. -Who?
每个人
Everyone.
这件...
lt's....
这件大衣真不错
lt's a nice coat.
当你和坏人同流合污 会同情他们吗?
When you lived among the criminals, did you start to pity them?
会的 当我第一次为了吃饭偷东西时
The first time I stole so that I wouldn't starve, yes.
我突然失去了是非善恶的观念
I lost many assumptions about the simple nature of right and wrong.
当我到处闯荡
And when I traveled...
我尝到犯罪前的恐惧
...I learned the fear before a crime...
以及得手后的兴奋
...and the thrill of success.
但是我从来没变成坏人
But I never became one of them.
他不想说他的名字
我管你叫什么 你只是个犯人
Fool. What do l care what your name is? You're a criminal.
我不是犯人
I'm not a criminal
你去和这批货的主人说吧
Tell that to the guy who owned these.
(韦恩企业 中国制造)
你为了克服内心恐惧 并洞悉犯罪心理而走遍全世界
You've traveled the world to understand the criminal mind and conquer your fears.
但是罪犯的内心并不复杂
But a criminal is not complicated.
你真正害怕的是自己的内心
And what you really fear is inside yourself.
你害怕你自己的力量
You fear your own power.
你也害怕你内心的愤怒...
You fear your anger...
会逼你做出伟大或可怕的事
...the drive to do great or terrible things.
你必须克服你的内心恐惧
Now you must journey inwards.
准备好了
You are ready.
吸气
Breathe.
用力吸气
把你的恐惧吸进去
Breathe in your fears.
面对你的恐惧
Face them.
你要成为恐惧本身 才能克服它
To conquer fear, you must become fear.
你必须造成别人的恐惧
You must bask in the fear of other men.
而大家都害怕看不见的东西
And men fear most what they cannot see.
你必须让人想到你就害怕
You have to become a terrible thought.
成为死神化身
A wraith.
让坏人闻风丧胆
You have to become an idea!
感受恐惧如何模糊你的感官
Feel terror cloud your senses.
让恐惧的力量扭曲你的身心
Feel its power to distort.
掌控你的一切
To control.
这股恐惧的力量才会属于你
And know that this power can be yours.
拥抱你最深层的恐惧
Embrace your worst fear.
和恐惧的黑暗力量融为一体
Become one with the darkness.
全神贯注
Focus.
全心投入
Concentrate.
随心所欲控制你的全身
Master your senses.
你不能露出你的行踪
You cannot leave any sign.
我并没有
l haven't.
很好
lmpressive.
我们已经消除你的恐惧
We have purged your fear.
你可以当这批勇士的首领
You are ready to lead these men.
你可以加入影武者联盟
You are ready to become a member of the League of Shadows.
但首先要证明你矢志维护正义
But first, you must demonstrate your commitment to justice.
不
No.
我不是刽子手
l'm no executioner.
敌人不会对你手下留情
Your compassion is a weakness your enemies will not share.
这才是重点
That's why it's so important.
这就是我们和他们的不同
lt separates us from them.
你想打击犯罪 他就是杀人犯
You want to fight criminals. This man is a murderer.
- 他应该接受审判 - 受谁审判?
-This man should be tried. -By whom?
让贪污腐败的法官来审判?
Corrupt bureaucrats?
坏人根本没把法律放在眼里
Criminals mock society's laws.
你比任何人都清楚这一点
You know this better than most.
你不能率领他们
You cannot lead these men...
除非你能不择手段打击犯罪
...unless you are prepared to do what is necessary to defeat evil.
我要率领他们到哪里?
And where would l be leading these men?
高谭市
Gotham.
你是高谭市的天之骄子
As Gotham's favored son...
你有能力瓦解高谭市的恶势力
...you will be ideally placed to strike at the heart of criminality.
- 我该怎么做? - 高谭市的气数已尽
-How? -Gotham's time has come.
就跟君士坦丁堡和古罗马一样
Like Constantinople or Rome before it...
高谭市已经沦为万恶的城市
...the city has become a breeding ground for suffering and injustice.
它无可救药 必须将它毁灭
lt is beyond saving and must be allowed to die.
这是影武者联盟最重要的任务
This is the most important function of the League of Shadows.
也是我们数百年来的使命
lt is one we've performed for centuries.
高谭市...
Gotham...
一定要被摧毁
...must be destroyed.
你不会信这种鬼话吧?
You can't believe in this.
忍者大师将我们从 内心最黑暗的角落拯救出来
Ra's al Ghul rescued us from the darkest corners of our own hearts.
他要求我们以勇气 行当行之事回报他
What he asks in return is the courage to do what is necessary.
我会回高谭市对付这类坏人
l will go back to Gotham and l will fight men like this...
但是我不会当刽子手
...but l will not become an executioner.
布鲁斯 别这样
Bruce, please.
你要想清楚 你已不能回头
For your own sake, there is no turning back.
- 你是在干什么? - 行我当行之事
-What are you doing? -What's necessary, my friend.
我会跟他说你救他一命
l will tell him you saved his life.
韦恩少爷 你消失好一阵子
Master Wayne, you've been gone a long time.
- 是啊 - 你这身打扮很时髦
-Yes, l have. -You look very fashionable.
只是有点脏
Apart from the mud.
你这次会待很久吗?
Are you coming back to Gotham for long, sir?
需要待多久就待多久
As long as it takes.
我要让高谭市市民知道
l want to show the people...
这城市不属于贪官与罪犯
...their city doesn't belong to the criminals and the corrupt.
经济大萧条期间你爸为了消弭贫穷
ln the depression, your father nearly bankrupted Wayne Enterprises...
几乎倾家荡产
...combating poverty.
他相信他能让有钱人共襄盛举 拯救高谭市
He believed his example could inspire the wealthy of Gotham to save their city.
他成功了吗?
Did it?
算是吧
ln a way.
他惨遭谋杀 为有钱有势的人敲响警钟
Their murder shocked the wealthy and the powerful into action.
人们的漠不关心 唯有戏剧性大逆转才能唤醒
People need dramatic examples to shake them out of apathy.
身为布鲁斯韦恩做不了什么
l can't do that as Bruce Wayne.
我只是个血肉之躯
As a man...
很容易被忽视、摧毁
...l'm flesh and blood, l can be ignored, destroyed.
但是成为正义化身
But as a symbol....
我就永远不会被击败
As a symbol, l can be incorruptible.
- 永远正气长存 - 什么化身?
-l can be everlasting. -What symbol?
一种原始的...
Something elemental...
可怕的化身
...something terrifying.
你单枪匹马对抗犯罪集团
l assume that as you take on the underworld...
我以为这化身是会 保护你关心的人不被报复
...this symbol is a persona to protect those you care about from reprisals?
你说的是瑞秋吗?
You're thinking about Rachel?
其实我说的是我自己
Actually, sir, l was thinking of myself.
有人知道我回来吗?
Have you told anyone l'm coming back?
我不敢让人知道你死而复生
l couldn't figure the legal ramifications of bringing you back from the dead.
- 死而复生? - 你失踪了七年
-Dead? -You've been gone seven years.
你对外宣布我死了?
You had me declared dead?
其实是厄尔先生 他要让公司上市
Actually, it was Mr. Earle. He's taking the company public.
他也要把你的股票卖掉
He wanted to liquidate your majority shareholding.
那些股票值很多钱
Those shares are worth quite a bit of money.
幸好我把全部财产都留给你
Well, it's a good thing l left everything to you, then.
是的 少爷
Quite so, sir.
我的劳斯莱斯可以借你开 回来时别忘了加满油
And you can borrow the Rolls, if you like. Just bring it back with a full tank.
我认为萨兹先生会试图自杀并危害他人
ln my opinion, Mr. Zsaz is as much a danger to himself as to others...
因此监狱并不适合他
...and prison is probably not the best environment for his rehabilitation.
- 克莱恩医师 - 道斯小姐
-Dr. Crane. -Miss Dawes.
你真的认为黑道杀手不该坐牢?
You think a man who butchers people for the mob doesn't belong in jail?
我若不这么认为 就不会替他辩护
l would hardly have testified to that otherwise, would l?
费康尼老大有三个杀手
This is the third of Falcone's thugs you've had declared insane...
被你送进精神疗养院
...and moved into your asylum.
混黑道一定很容易被逼疯
Well, the work offered by organized crime must have an attraction to the insane.
或是被收买
Or the corrupt.
芬奇先生
Mr. Finch.
你最好劝劝道斯小姐
You should check with Miss Dawes here...
不要无凭无据对我提出指控
...just what implications your office has authorized her to make. lf any.
- 瑞秋 你这是在做什么? - 你又是在做什么 卡尔?
-What are you doing? -What are you doing, Carl?
我是在保护你
Looking out for you.
费康尼收买了一半的政府官员
Falcone has half the city bought and paid for.
- 放弃吧 - 你怎么能这么说?
-Drop it. -How can you say that?
我痛恨费康尼 但我更关心你
Because as much as l care about getting Falcone, l care more about you.
我知道你对我好
That's sweet.
但我不能接受
We've been through all that.
又有一只蝙蝠飞进来
Blessed bat again, sir.
他们的巢穴一定在地底
They nest somewhere in the grounds.
我不帮你了 有人对我起疑心
No more favors. Someone is sniffing around.
我帮你 你帮我
Hey, l scratch your back, you scratch mine, doc.
我替你们把货运进来
l'm bringing in the shipments.
我们有付你钱
We are paying you for that.
付钱并不算是帮我的忙
Maybe money isn't as interesting to me as favors.
我知道你并不怕我 费康尼先生
l am more than aware that you are not intimidated by me, Mr. Falcone.
但是等我的老板来了以后...
But you know who l'm working for, and when he gets here...
他要来高谭市?
He... He's coming to Gotham?
是的
Yes, he is.
他来了以后会想听到...
And when he gets here, he's not going to wanna hear...
你为了几个小混混危害我们的行动
...that you have endangered our operation just to get your thugs out of a little jail time.
- 谁在找你麻烦? - 地检署的一个女孩
-Who's bothering you? -There's a girl at the DA's office.
- 我们用钱收买她 - 她不要钱
-We'll buy her off. -Not this one.
原来是理想主义者
ldealist, huh?
我也有办法对付这种人
Well, there's an answer to that too.
- 我并不想知道 - 你非知道不可
-l don't want to know. -Yes, you do.
(韦恩大楼)
其它部门的业绩有稳健的成长
No, we are showing very healthy growth in these sectors.
汤犸斯韦恩绝对不会同意...
l don't think Thomas Wayne would have viewed heavy-arms manufacture...
让公司变成军火制造商
...as a suitable cornerstone for our business.
那是二十年前的事 佛德瑞
Well, that's 20 years ago, Fredericks.
汤犸斯韦恩都死了二十年
l think after 20 years we can allow ourselves...
我们不必再管他怎么想
...to stop thinking about what Thomas Wayne would have done.
早安 厄尔先生办公室
Good morning, Mr. Earle's office.
是的 他确定明天会出席晚宴
Yes, he's confirmed for the dinner tomorrow evening.
早安 我来见厄尔先生
Good morning. l'm here to see Mr. Earle.
请问贵姓大名?
Name?
布鲁斯韦恩
Bruce Wayne.
汤犸斯也许不会让公司上市
Thomas would probably not have taken the company public.
但我们为了公司一定要这么做
But that is what we, as responsible managers, are going to do.
洁西卡?
Jessica?
洁西卡? 你在哪里?
Jessica? Where are you?
- 盯着小白球看... - 你为什么不接电话?
-Eye on the ball, and.... -Why is no one answering the phone?
放心 对方一定会再打来
lt's Wayne Enterprises, Mr. Earle. l'm sure they'll call back.
布鲁斯? 你不是死了吗?
Bruce? You're supposed to be dead.
抱歉让你失望了
l'm sorry to disappoint.
- 你要看看这份文件 - 你见到他了吗?
-l need you to take a look at this. -Have you seen him yet?
- 谁? - 韦恩
-Who? -Wayne.
新闻整天都在播 他回来了
lt's been all over the news. He's back.
请你了解这件事势在必行
l'm sure you realize l can't stop the big machine.
时势如此
Too many wheels turning.
- 公司一定要上市 - 我了解
-We're going public. -l understand.
我也会分到不少钱
And l'll be handsomely rewarded for my shares.
我并不想干涉公司行政
l'm not looking to interfere.
- 我只想要一份工作 - 哦?
-l am looking for a job. -Oh?
我想多了解我的家族企业
l just want to get to know the company that my family built.
你想先进哪个部门?
Any ideas where you would start?
我对应用科技部门有兴趣
Applied Sciences caught my eye.
福克斯的部门
Fox's department.
我会通知他
l'll let him know you're coming.
你跟你爸长得很像
You look like him. Your dad.
你是韦恩家族唯一的遗孤
You're the only one left of the Wayne family.
这是你的家 欢迎回家
This is where you belong. Welcome home.
环保科技、军火、消费产品
Environmental procedures, defense projects, consumer products.
全都是实验原型 并没有进入量产阶段
All prototypes. None in production.
- 完全没有 - 完全没有?
-On any level whatsoever. -None?
他们是怎么跟你说这部门的?
What did they tell you this place was?
他们什么都没说
They didn't tell me anything.
厄尔倒是跟我说得很明白
Earle told me exactly what it was when he sent me down here.
我被打入冷宫
Dead end.
好让我不在董事会上找麻烦
Place to keep me from causing the board any more trouble.
来吧
Come on.
- 你曾经是公司董事? - 当你父亲还在的时候
-You were on the board? -When your father ran things.
- 你认识我父亲? - 是啊
-You knew my father? -Oh, yeah.
我协助他建造高架铁路系统
Helped him build his train.
到了
Here we are.
多功能强化防护带
Kevlar utility harness.
汽动式磁力钩爪枪
Gas-powered, magnetic grapple gun.
承受重量高达158公斤
The 350-pound test monofilament.
你爸设计的铁路系统很棒
Wonderful project, your dad's train.
每一条路线都直达韦恩大楼 水电管线也直接连到这里
Routed it right into Wayne Tower, along with the water and power utilities.
让韦恩大楼成为高谭市的命脉
Kind of made Wayne Tower the unofficial center of Gotham City.
厄尔却让它荒废 请看
Of course, Earle let it go to rot. Here we are.
先锋部队的装甲衣
Nomex survival suit for advanced infantry.
克维拉纤维 强化护肘护膝
Kevlar biweave, reinforced joints.
- 防裂材质? - 连刀都刺不穿
-Tear-resistant? -This sucker will stop a knife.
- 防弹吗? - 刀枪不入
-Bulletproof? -Anything but a straight shot.
为什么不量产?
Why didn't they put it into production?
军方认为士兵的命不值30万元
Bean counters didn't think a soldier's life was worth 300 grand.
你为什么对这些感兴趣?
So, what's your interest in it, Mr. Wayne?
我想借来用
l want to borrow it.
我要做洞穴探险
For spelunking.
洞穴探险?
Spelunking?
对 到山洞探险
Yeah, you know, cave diving?
有人会在山洞向你开枪吗?
You expecting to run into much gunfire in these caves?
我不希望让厄尔知道...
Look, l'd rather Mr. Earle didn't know about me borrowing...
韦恩先生
Mr. Wayne...
对我来说
...the way l see it...
这一切都是你的
...all this stuff is yours anyway.
好了 试试看
Okay. Give it a try.
真是个好地方
Charming.
至少你有很多同伴
At least you'll have company.
这一定是东南厢房的地基
This must be the lowest foundation of the southeast wing.
你曾祖父在内战时透过地下管道
ln the Civil War, your great-great-grandfather was involved in the Underground Railroad...
秘密将黑奴运送来北方
...secretly transporting freed slaves to the North...
我怀疑就是偷藏在这些洞穴
...and l suspect these caverns came in handy.
阿尔弗雷德 过来看看
Alfred! Come up here!
我在这里就看得见 多谢了
l can see everything all right from down here, sir, thank you.
头罩的主要零件来自新加坡
We order the main part of this cowl from Singapore.
透过傀儡公司进口
Via a dummy corporation.
是的
lndeed. And then, quite separately...
这零件则是向中国公司订购
...we place an order to a Chinese company for these.
- 然后我们自己组装 - 没错
-Put it together ourselves. -Precisely.
大量订购才不会让人起疑
They'll have to be large orders, to avoid suspicion.
- 有多少? - 一万个
-How large? -Say 1 0,000.
- 至少会有很多备用品 - 是啊
-Well, at least we'll have spares. -Yes.
你不分一杯羹吗?
Don't suppose you want a taste.
我在想也许有一天你会学聪明
l just keep offering, thinking maybe someday you'll get wise.
你这么做一点都不聪明
There's nothing wise in what you do, Flass.
老詹 你不收贿让大家很紧张
Well, Jimbo, you don't take the taste, makes us guys nervous.
我不会告密
l'm no rat.
大家都被收买 我能向谁告状?
ln a town this bent, who's there to rat to anyway?
别转身
Don't turn around.
你是硕果仅存的好警察
You're a good cop. One of the few.
你要干什么?
What do you want?
费康尼每星期都进一批毒品
Carmine Falcone brings in shipments of drugs every week.
为什么没人阻止他?
Nobody takes him down. Why?
他收买了警察和法官
He's paid up with the right people.
该怎么做才能制止他?
What will it take to bring him down?
向斐登法官施压
Leverage on Judge Faden...
找一个有胆识的检察官
...and a DA brave enough to prosecute.
瑞秋道斯
Rachel Dawes.
你是谁?
Who are you?
注意我的信号
Watch for my sign.
你只有一个人?
You're just one man?
现在我们有两个人
Now we're two.
我们?
We?
站住!
Freeze!
那是什么人?
What the hell was that?
只是一个疯子
Just some nut.
今天你又要去洞穴探险吗?
Well, what is it today? More spelunking?
不 今天我要定点跳伞
No. Today it's BASE-jumping.
定点跳伞?
BASE-jumping.
- 像是高空跳伞吗? - 差不多
-That like parachuting? -Kind of.
你有轻质布料吗?
Do you have any lightweight fabrics?
我正好有你要的布料
You know, l think l have just the thing.
这叫记忆布料 看到吗?
lt's called memory cloth. Notice anything?
和一般布料一样轻柔
Regularly flexible...
但是一旦通上电流
...but put a current through it...
- 分子重新组合后就会变硬 - 你可以做成什么形状? ?
-...molecules realign, it becomes rigid. -What kind of shapes can you make?
只要有骨架 什么形状都行
Can be tailored to fit any structure based on a rigid skeleton.
军方又嫌太贵吗?
Too expensive for the Army?
他们没想到亿万富翁会有兴趣 去洞穴探险或定点跳伞
l don't think they tried to market it to the billionaire, spelunking, BASE-jumping crowd.
- 福克斯先生 - 是的
-Look, Mr. Fox. -Yes, sir?
如果你觉得不妥...
lf you're uncomfortable...
只要你不跟我实话实说
Mr. Wayne, if you don't want to tell me exactly what you're doing...
我被问到就不必说谎
...when l'm asked, l don't have to lie.
不过别以为我是傻子
But don't think of me as an idiot.
好吧
Fair enough.
那是什么?
What's that?
那辆弹力车?
The Tumbler?
你不会有兴趣的
Oh, you wouldn't be interested in that.
这是造桥用的越野车
She was built as a bridging vehicle.
作战时可以拉着缆绳跳过河流
During combat, two of these would jump over a river, towing cables.
只要让推进器全速前进
Over here on the throttle, flip that open and throttle up.
它就能越过任何障碍 不要乱来!
This will boost you into a rampless jump... Not now!
小子 别乱来
Not... Not now, sir.
关闭再燃装置
Afterburner disengaged.
我们一直没办法造桥
We never could get the damn bridge to work...
不过这辆车性能超强
...but this baby works just fine.
你觉得怎样?
So, what do you think?
有黑色车款吗?
Does it come in black?
我要你星期四到码头
I need you at the docks Thursday.
- 有麻烦吗? - 最后一批货...
-Problems? -l don't want any trouble...
- 不能出错 - 好吧
-...with the last shipment. -Sure.
听说有一位检察官在找你麻烦
Word on the street is you got a beef with somebody in the DA's office.
- 是吗? - 听说你肯付...
-ls that right? -And that there's a fat prize...
一大笔钱把她除掉
...waiting for anybody willing to do anything about it.
你想说什么 佛莱斯警官?
So, what's your point, Mr. Flass?
你看过那女孩吗?
Have you seen the girl?
她是个美女助理检察官
It's a cute little assistant DA.
拿她开刀不太好吧?
Don't you think that's a little bit too much heat to bring down, maybe?
- 你会激起众怒 - 别太高估高谭市的治安
-Even for this town. -Never underestimate Gotham City.
每天都有人下班被抢
People get mugged coming home from work every day of the week.
有时候就是会莫名其妙走霉运
Sometimes... Sometimes things just go bad.
这批货的石墨含量太高
lt's a problem with the graphite, sir.
下一批货一定没问题
The next 1 0,000 will be up to specifications.
- 至少厂商给我们打了折 - 是啊
-At least they gave us a discount. -Quite.
我建议你最好暂时不要撞到头
ln the meantime, sir, may l suggest you try to avoid landing on your head?
你为什么选择蝙蝠?
Why bats, Master Wayne?
蝙蝠让我感到恐惧
Bats frighten me.
我也要让敌人一样畏惧我
lt's time my enemies shared my dread.
这是干嘛?
What is this?
继续干活吧
Continue.
看起来没问题
Looks fine out there.
玩具熊直接交给毒贩吗?
The bears go straight to the dealers.
对 玩具兔要运到奈何岛
Yeah, and the rabbits go to the man in the Narrows.
- 这两种毒品有什么不同? - 你最好不要知道
-What's the difference? -lgnorance is bliss, my friend.
你惹不起那些大魔头
Don't burden yourself with the secrets of scary people.
小史?
Hey. Steiss.
Steiss?
干嘛?
What?
搞什么?
What the...?
我最好去看看
l better check it.
大事不妙 你最好闪人
There's a problem out here. You better bail.
你在哪里?
Where are you?!
这里
Here.
快开车 哦 要命!
Get going. Oh, shit.
你是什么东西?
What the hell are you?
我是蝙蝠侠
l'm Batman.
好帅的大衣
Nice coat.
谢了
Thanks.
别过来
Hold it.
给我滚远一点
That's right, you better run.
费康尼派他们来杀你
Falcone sent them to kill you.
- 为什么? - 你把他惹毛了
-Why? -You rattled his cage.
- 这是什么? - 你的筹码
-What's this? -Leverage.
- 用来做什么? - 把坏人绳之以法
-For what? -To get things moving.
你是谁?
Who are you?
像你一样
Someone like you.
想要伸张正义的人
Someone who'll rattle the cages.
小姐 你没事吧?
Ma'am? Everything okay?
- 他们是费康尼的手下? - 逮到他们也没用
-Falcone's men? -Does it matter?
费康尼一样有办法脱身
We'll never tie him to it anyway.
这次他脱不了身
l wouldn't be too sure of that.
这是怎么回事?
What the hell is that?
把他放下来
Cut him down.
(蝙蝠侠逮到黑帮老大)
这不可原谅
Unacceptable.
我不管他是帮派死对头、守护天使
Now, l don't care if it's rival gangs, Guardian Angels...
或是什么救世主
...or the goddamn Salvation Army...
把他抓起来 别让他出风头
...get them off the street and off the front page.
听说他是一个人 或是一个怪物
They say it was just one guy. Or a creature.
他只是奇装异服的怪胎
lt was some asshole in a costume.
- 干嘛? - 他抓到...
-Yeah? -This guy did deliver us...
势力最大的黑帮老大
...one of the city's biggest crime lords.
没人能在我的辖区动私刑
No one takes the law into their own hands in my city.
明白吗?
Understand?
- 他这次难逃法律制裁 - 斐登法官会罩他
-No way to bury it now. -There's still Judge Faden.
- 我能对付斐登法官 - 大家都说是一只蝙蝠干的?
-l've got Faden covered. -What about this bat they're babbling about?
就算他们作证说是大蝙蝠干的
Even if these guys will swear to being thrashed by a giant bat...
费康尼还是被逮个正着
...we've got Falcone at the scene.
蝙蝠侠把他犯案的证据都给我
Drugs, prints, cargo manifests. This bat character gave us everything.
那就起诉他吧
Okay. Let's do it.
- 蝙蝠是夜行动物 - 也许是吧
-Bats are nocturnal. -Bats may be.
不过你也不能睡到下午三点
But even for billionaire playboys, 3:00 is pushing it.
这是过双重生活的代价
The price for leading a double life, l fear.
你制造的戏剧效果很唬人
Your theatrics made an impression.
戏剧效果和障眼法...
Theatricality and deception...
能打击犯罪 这是好的开始
...are powerful weapons, Alfred. This is a good start.
如果你以后会一直受伤
lf those are to be the first of many injuries to come...
就要找很好的借口
...it would be wise to find a suitable excuse.
比如说打马球
Polo, for instance.
我又不会打马球
l'm not learning polo, Alfred.
无缘无故受伤 缺乏社交生活
Strange injuries, a nonexistent social life.
大家一定会怀疑
These things beg the question...
布鲁斯韦恩大少爷都在搞什么鬼
...as to what exactly does Bruce Wayne do with his time and his money.
像我这种人都做什么?
What does someone like me do?
开名贵跑车 泡漂亮女星
Drive sports cars, date movie stars.
买一些别人买不起的东西
Buy things that are not for sale.
韦恩少爷 当你假装找乐子
Who knows, Master Wayne, you start pretending to have fun...
也许真的会找到快乐
...you might even have a little by accident.
老板
Sir.
- 出了状况 - 什么事?
-We have a situation. -All right.
海巡队昨晚发现我们的货轮
The Coast Guard picked up one of our cargo ships last night...
船身受损 船员失踪 大概全都丧命
...heavily damaged, all crew missing, probably dead.
货轮载了一具微波发射器
The ship was carrying a prototype weapon. It's a microwave emitter.
是用来进行沙漠战争的
lt's designed for desert warfare, but it...
但是看起来有人...
lt looks like somebody...
利用它杀人
...turned it on.
它能发射微波蒸发敌人的供水
lt uses focused microwaves to vaporize the enemy's water supply.
货轮严重受损
The damage to the ship was catastrophic.
那具武器也...
The weapon itself is....
不见了?
Missing?
对
Yeah.
韦恩先生
Mr. Wayne.
这辆车好酷
Nice car.
我的另一辆车更酷
You should see my other one.
他逮到警方抓不到的大坏蛋
He's done something the police never have.
他不能动用私刑
You can't take the law into your own hands.
至少他在打击犯罪
Well, at least he's getting something done.
布鲁斯 你来评评理
Bruce, help me out here.
一个扮成蝙蝠的人一定有毛病
Well, a guy who dresses up like a bat clearly has issues.
可是他把费康尼关起来
But he's put Falcone behind bars.
警方并不领情 那代表什么?
Now the cops want to bring him in. What does that tell you?
那代表他们嫉妒他
They're jealous.
水池是装饰用的
Sir, the pool is for decoration...
不能下去游泳
...and your friends do not have swimwear.
她们是欧洲豪放女
Well, they're European.
我要请你们离开
l'm going to have to ask you to leave.
你给我再多小费也没用
-lt is not a question of money.
你看着...
Well, you see...
我要买下这家饭店
...l'm buying this hotel...
新规定 从今以后水池可以游泳
...and setting some new rules about the pool area.
我觉得应该颁奖给蝙蝠侠
l think the Batman deserves a medal.
把他送进疯人院才对
And a straitjacket to pin it on.
谢谢
Thank you.
布鲁斯?
Bruce?
瑞秋?
Rachel?
我听说你回来了
l'd heard you were back.
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
只是泡泡水 见到你真好
Just swimming here. Wow, it is good to see you.
你离开了好久
You were gone a long time.
- 是啊 你好吗? - 老样子
-l know. How are things? -The same.
工作越来越辛苦
Job's getting worse.
光靠自己是不能改变世界的
Can't change the world on your own.
我没有别的选择
What choice do l have...
你只会忙着和辣妹泡水
...when you're too busy swimming?
瑞秋 这...
Rachel, all of...
这一切
All this....
不是真正的我
lt's... lt's not me. lt's....
其实我的内心...
lnside, l am....
并没有这么肤浅
l am more.
快来嘛 布鲁斯
Come on, Bruce. Come on.
咱们再去多买几家饭店
Bruce, we have some more hotels for you to buy.
布鲁斯
Bruce...
你内心深处仍是那个正直的小孩
...deep down you may still be that same great kid you used to be.
但是在你外表底下是谁并不重要
But it's not who you are underneath...
你的所作所为才重要
...it's what you do that defines you.
克莱恩医师 谢谢你来访
Dr. Crane, thanks for coming.
不客气 他想割腕自杀?
Not at all. He cut his wrists?
他想装疯脱罪 不过万一出事...
Probably looking for the insanity plea. But if anything should happen....
还是保险一点比较好
Of course, better safe than sorry.
我受不了了 我快发疯了
Yeah, Dr. Crane, l can't take it anymore. lt's all too much.
我一定要出去
The walls are closing in. Blah, blah, blah.
再吃几天牢饭我真的会发疯
A couple of days of this food, it'll be true.
- 你要什么? - 我要知道...
-What do you want? -l wanna know...
你打算怎么让我闭嘴
...how you're gonna convince me to keep my mouth shut.
你什么都不知道
About what? You don't know anything.
我知道你怕警方仔细查那批毒品
l know you don't want the cops to take a closer look at the drugs they seized.
也知道你替囚犯进行人体实验
And l know about your experiments with the inmates of your nut house.
我一定会先查出合伙人的底细
See, l don't go into business with a guy without finding out his dirty secrets.
你找来的打手
And those goons you used.
都是我的人
l own the muscle in this town.
我一直替你把货运进来
Now, l've been bringing your stuff in for months...
你的老板一定想大干一票 要算我一份
...so whatever he's planning, it's big, and l want in.
我知道他会怎么说
Well, l already know what he'll say.
我们应该杀了你灭口
That we should kill you.
他在我的地盘动不了我
Even he can't get me in here. Not in my town.
你想看我的面具吗?
Would you like to see my mask?
我用它来做实验
l use it in my experiments.
你这大恶人不会觉得可怕
Now, l'm probably not very frightening to a guy like you.
不过疯子就会被吓死
But these crazies, they can't stand it.
原来疯人院是你这疯子开的
So when did the nut take over the nut house?
他们都跟你一样
They scream and they cry...
大哭大叫
...much as you're doing now.
他这次并不是装疯
Well, he's not faking. Not that one.
我会和法官谈谈 把他送到我的精神病院
l'll talk to the judge and see if l can get him moved...
他待在这儿没有救
...to the secure wing at Arkham. l can't treat him here.
一场大风暴即将来临
Storm's coming.
你逮到费康尼让黑道很紧张
The scum is getting jumpy because you stood up to Falcone.
你的搭档和费康尼挂勾
lt's a start. Your partner was at the docks with Falcone.
他有时候也帮黑道办事
Well, he moonlights as a low-level enforcer.
毒品分成两半 一半交给毒贩
They were splitting the shipment in two. Only half went to the dealers.
那另一半呢?
Why? What about the other half?
- 佛莱斯知道 - 他不会说
-Flass knows. -He won't talk.
他一定会跟我说
He'll talk to me.
罗柏局长成立专案小组追捕你
Commissioner Loeb set up a massive task force to catch you.
- 他认为你是危险人物 - 你认为呢?
-He thinks you're dangerous. -What do you think?
我认为你想尽力帮忙
l think you're trying to help.
不过有时候我会看错人
But l've been wrong before.
快点 别慢吞吞
Come on, l ain't got all night.
拜托 我有小孩要养
Flass, l have kids to feed.
他们不爱吃三明治吗?
What, they don't like falafel?
另一批毒品在哪里?
Where were the other drugs going?
我不知道
l never knew. l don't know.
- 我对天发誓 - 对我发誓
-l swear to God. -Swear to me!
我一直都不知道
l don't... l don't know. l never knew. Never.
那批毒品先送去给另一个人
They went to some guy for a couple days before they went to the dealers.
为什么?
Why?
他在毒品里加了其它的料
There was something... Something else in the drugs...
- 不知名的料 - 什么料?
-...something hidden. -What?
我只知道那批货被送到奈何岛
l never went to the drop-off point. lt was in the Narrows.
- 警察只有成群结队武装起来才敢去 - 我像是警察吗?
-Cops only go there when they're in force. -Do l look like a cop?
不!
No...
就是这箱货柜
This is the one l'm talking about.
- 有问题吗? - 它不该存在的
-What's your problem with it? -lt shouldn't exist.
从新加坡出发时只有246箱 现在却有247箱
This ship left Singapore with 246 containers, but arrived with 247.
这里面一定有违禁品
l'm guessing there's something l'm not supposed to find in there.
我们不敢查费康尼老大的货柜
Listen, counselor, we don't wanna know what's in Mr. Falcone's crate.
现在情况不同了 快打开来
Things are working a little differently now. Open it up.
(韦恩企业)
这到底是什么?
What the hell is this?
就是你 大家都在说你
lt's you, isn't it? Everybody's been talking about you.
快进来!
Get in here!
别的小朋友一定不相信的
The other kids won't believe me.
湮灭所有证据
Get rid of all traces.
- 放火把这地方烧掉 - 好吧
-Better torch the whole place. -All right.
你不舒服吗?
Having trouble?
坐下来 喝口水
Take a seat. Have a drink.
你看起来火气很大
You look like a man who takes himself too seriously.
我觉得你应该降降火气
Do you want my opinion? You need to lighten up.
阿尔弗雷德? 阿尔弗雷德?
Alfred, help me.
我中了毒...替我验血
Blood. Take. Take poison. Blood poison.
中毒 中毒了
Poisonous. Poisonous.
布鲁斯
Bruce...
我们为什么跌倒?
...why do we fall?
- 我昏迷了多久? - 两天
-How long was l out? -Two days.
今天是你生日
lt's your birthday.
祝你生日幸福快乐
Many happy returns.
我有过这种经验 这次更强烈
l've felt these effects before, but this was so much more potent.
这是一种迷幻药 被做成喷剂当作武器
lt was some kind of hallucinogen, weaponized, in aerosol form.
你一定是在夜店被人下了药
You have been hanging out in the wrong clubs, Mr. Wayne.
是我把福克斯先生请来
l called Mr. Fox when your condition worsened after the first day.
我替你验血 把接受体合成物 和蛋白质催化素分离出来
l analyzed your blood, isolating the receptor compounds and the protein-based catalyst.
你能不能说白话?
Am l meant to understand any of that?
可以 我费了好一番功夫
Not at all. l just wanted you to know how hard it was.
- 终于制造出一种抗体 - 你可以制造更多吗?
-Bottom line, l synthesized an antidote. -Could you make more?
你打算再吸毒吗?
You planning on gassing yourself again, Mr. Wayne?
你也知道 泡夜店狂欢
Well, you know how it is. You're out at night, looking for kicks...
总是有被下迷幻药的风险
...someone's passing around the weaponized hallucinogens....
我把手上有的给你 注射抗体后就不怕被下药
l'll bring what l have. The antidote should inoculate you for now.
阿尔弗雷德 很高兴见到你
Alfred, always a pleasure.
卢修
Lucius.
- 你真的不进来吗? - 我得赶回去
-You sure you don't want to come in? -l have to get back.
- 请你转交给他 - 谢谢你
-l wanted to leave this. -Thank you.
瑞秋?
Rachel?
看来有人在蜡烛两头烧
Looks like someone's been burning the candle at both ends.
- 你昨晚一定玩得很疯 - 今天是我生日
-Must've been quite an occasion. -lt is my birthday.
我知道 今晚我不能来 我只是来送礼物
l know. l'm sorry l can't come tonight. l was just dropping off your present.
- 你有别的事要忙吗? - 我的上司失踪了两天
-You've got better plans? -My boss has been missing for two days...
这代表我要开始找他的尸体
...which means l should probably start by looking at the bottom of the river.
- 瑞秋 - 对不起
-Rachel. -Excuse me.
瑞秋道斯
Rachel Dawes.
是谁下的命令? 无论如何都要把克莱恩找来
Who authorized that? Get Crane down there now. Don't take no for an answer.
请李曼医师明天一早交出报告
Call Dr. Lehmann, tell him we need our own assessment on the judge's desk by morning.
- 怎么了? - 费康尼出事了
-What's wrong? -lt's Falcone.
克莱恩把费康尼送到精神病院
Dr. Crane moved him to Arkham Asylum on suicide watch.
亚克汉疗养院在奈何岛 你现在要去?
You're going to Arkham now? lt's in the Narrows, Rachel.
你去狂欢吧 布鲁斯
You enjoy your party, Bruce.
- 我得去工作 - 你千万要小心
-Some of us have work to do. -You be careful.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
(谁找到就是谁的)
少爷 客人就快来了
But, Master Wayne, the guests will be arriving.
趁我回来之前
Keep them happy until l arrive.
说笑话给他们听
Tell them that joke you know.
玩得开心吗?
Having fun?
比尔? 你这大人物怎么会跑来这里?
Bill? Now, what's a big shot like you doing in a place like this?
我要一些资料
l need some information.
韦恩企业47B、1ME型产品
The Wayne Enterprise 47-B, 1 -ME.
1ME型
1 -ME.
能够蒸发敌人供水的微波发射器
lt's a microwave emitter. lt was designed to vaporize an enemy's water supply.
听说被实验用来在空中散播化学物
Rumor was they tested dispersing water-based chemical agents into the air...
这不是不合法吗?
...but isn't that illegal?
我要这项实验的所有资料
l want all the information on the development of this project...
立刻把备份档案和文件送来
...all data, files, backup disks, on my desk right away.
你弄丢了吗?
Did you lose one?
我要把这部门和档案部合并
l'm merging your department with Archives.
我也要开除你
And l am firing you.
你没收到通知吗?
Didn't you get the memo?
稻草人
Scarecrow.
道斯小姐 你不必来这里
Miss Dawes, this is most irregular.
我把报告都交给法官了
l have nothing to add to the report l filed with the judge.
- 你的报告有疑点 - 什么疑点?
-l have questions about your report. -Such as?
一个没有精神病史的52岁中年人
lsn't it convenient for a 52-year-old man who has no history of mental illness...
怎么会在起诉前突然完全精神崩溃?
...to suddenly have a psychotic breakdown just when he's about to be indicted?
你也看到他的病情有多严重
Well, as you can see for yourself, there is nothing convenient about his symptoms.
- 稻草人 - 稻草人是什么?
-Scarecrow. -What's ''scarecrow''?
产生幻觉的精神病患
Patients suffering delusional episodes often focus their paranoia...
都会幻想被外在力量迫害
...on an external tormentor...
通常是某种可怕人物
...usually one conforming to Jungian archetypes.
他的幻觉是稻草人
ln this case, a scarecrow.
- 他服了药? - 我专攻精神病药物学
-He's drugged? -Psychopharmacology is my primary field.
我强烈支持用药物控制精神疾病
I'm a strong advocate.
他在外面呼风唤雨
Outside, he was a giant.
在这里只能乖乖听话
ln here, only the mind can grant you power.
你很得意 对吧?
You enjoy the reversal.
我认为精神胜于肉体
l respect the mind's power over the body.
所以我专门治疗精神病患
lt's why l do what l do.
但我专门把坏人关进牢里 不是住在疯人院
l do what l do to keep thugs like Falcone behind bars, not in therapy.
我要另外请医师为他进行诊断
l want my own psychiatric consultant to have full access to Falcone...
包括验血 查出你到底给他吃什么药
...including blood work. Find out what exactly you put him on.
- 请他明天一早再来 - 他今晚就会来
-First thing tomorrow, then. -Tonight.
我已经通知了李曼医师
l've already paged Dr. Lehmann at County General.
随你便
As you wish.
这里请
This way, please.
我要给你看样东西
There's something l think you should see.
这里是我们的药厂
This is where we make the medicine.
你也该吃一点药 让头脑清醒
Perhaps you should have some, clear your head.
谁知道你来这里?
Who knows you're here?
谁知道?
Who knows?
他在这里
He's here.
谁?
Who?
蝙蝠侠
The Batman.
- 我们该怎么办? - 有坏人闯进来...
-What do we do? -What anyone does...
该怎么办?
...when a prowler comes around.
- 报警呀 - 你要把警察找来?
-Call the police. -You want the cops here?
警察拿我们没办法
At this point, they can't stop us.
但是蝙蝠侠会坏事
But the Batman has a talent for disruption.
把他逼出去 让警察毙了他
Force him outside, the police will take him down. Go.
- 那她怎么办? - 她没救了
-What about her? -She hasn't got long.
我下的药很强 她撑不住的 快去吧
l gave her a concentrated dose. The mind can only take so much. Now go.
听说他很神?
The things they say about him.
他真的会飞吗?
Can he really fly?
我听说他能隐形
l heard he can disappear.
我们很快就会知道
Well, we'll find out.
不是吗?
Won't we?
这下你要自食其果了
Taste of your own medicine, doctor?
你在这里搞什么鬼?
What have you been doing here?
你替谁工作?
Who are you working for?
忍者...忍者大师
Ra's... Ra's al Ghul.
忍者大师死了 你替谁工作?
Ra's al Ghul is dead. Who are you working for?
克莱恩?
Crane.
克莱恩医师不在
Dr. Crane isn't here right now.
如果你想预约挂号...
But if you'd like to make an appointment....
蝙蝠侠 放下武器投降
Batman, put down your weapons and surrender.
你被包围了
You're surrounded.
- 你还在等什么? - 支援警力
-What are you waiting for? -Backup.
- 支援警力? - 蝙蝠侠在里面
-Backup? -The Batman's in there.
霹雳小组正赶来 如果你想冲进去...
SWAT's on the way. But if you wanna go in now...
我们会跟着你
...l'll be right behind you, sir.
等霹雳小组来了再说
SWAT's on the way.
- 喂 - 喂
-Hey. -Hey.
她怎么了?
What's happened to her?
她被克莱恩下了迷幻药 引发严重的恐慌症
Crane poisoned her with a psychotropic hallucinogen, a panic-inducing toxin.
- 我把她送到医院 - 没有用 我能救她
-Let me get her down to the medics. -They can't help her, but l can.
把她抱下去 在小巷等我
Get her downstairs. Meet me in the alley.
费康尼也被克莱恩下了药
Crane's been smuggling his toxin hidden in Falcone's drugs...
他也在高谭市的自来水管下药
...and they're dumping it into the water supply.
- 他想干什么? - 我不知道
-What was he planning? -l don't know.
他替费康尼工作吗?
Was he working for Falcone?
他提到另一个更可怕的人
He mentioned someone else, someone worse.
我得赶快为她注射抗体
She needs the antidote before the damage is permanent.
- 她还有多久时间? - 不久
-How long does she have? -Not long.
那是什么声音?
What is that?
- 支援来了 - 搞什么?
-Backup. -What the...?
抱歉
Excuse me.
- 她怎么样? - 她昏过去了 快走吧
-How is she? -She's fading. We gotta go.
我去开车
l'll get my car.
我开了我的车
l brought mine.
你的车?
Yours?
我也要弄一辆这么炫的车
l've gotta get me one of those.
- 他开车逃走 - 车款和颜色?
-He is in a vehicle. -Make and color?
那是辆黑色的...
lt's a black...
装甲车
...tank.
保持冷静
Stay calm.
你中毒了
You've been poisoned.
我追上去了
l'm on him.
慢慢呼吸
Breathe slowly.
撑着点
Hold on.
- 你在干嘛? - 抄近路
-What are you doing? -Shortcut.
挡住他的去路
Air One to ground, block that ramp.
他无处可逃
He's got no way off that roof.
马上熄火 乖乖下车
Turn off your engine. Step away from the car.
- 相信我 - 启动武器系统
-Trust me. -Weapons system activated.
这家伙到底是谁?
Who is this guy?
- 他去哪里? - 他在屋顶
-Where's he going? -He's on the roof.
- 他走哪一条街? - 不在街上
-What street is he taking? -He's not on a street.
他在屋顶上开车
He's flying on rooftops.
他的车到底长什么样子?
At least tell me what it looks like.
算了
Never mind.
追上了
Got him.
我们就跟在他后面
Coming right up on his butt.
嫌犯朝往州际公路开去
We're tracking suspect vehicle heading west on I- 1 7.
- 呼叫地面... - 他甩掉我们了
-Air One to ground. -l lost him.
我们失去他的踪影 九号出口已封闭
We've lost visual. Exit 9 is blocked.
我们去前面查查看
We'll loop back to check the frontage road.
启动秘密行动模式
Stealth mode activated.
保持清醒
Stay with me.
他在那里
What...? There he is.
撑着点
Just hold on.
瑞秋!
Rachel!
(福克斯给您的 阿尔弗雷德笔)
- 自来水管被下了毒药吗? - 没错
-They get any of this crap into the mains? -Yeah.
通知自来水厂 一定有办法... 全市的供水系统都被下药
Notify the water company. There's gotta be a way to isolate it.
他们一定花了几个星期下药
No. They put it all in. They must've been at this for weeks.
已经溶入全市的供水系统了
-Gotham's entire water supply is laced with it.
我们为什么没中毒?
-Why haven't we felt the effects?
这种毒药必须从肺部吸入
Must be a compound that has to be absorbed through the lungs.
你感觉如何?
How do you feel?
这是那里?
Where are we?
- 你为什么把我带来? - 我把你救回来 否则你就失常了
-Why did you bring me here? -lf l hadn't, your mind would now be lost.
- 你中了毒 - 是...
-You were poisoned. -lt was...
- 是克莱恩下的药 - 好好休息 克莱恩被戈登逮捕了
-lt was Dr. Crane. -Rest. Gordon has Crane.
戈登警官是你的朋友吗?
ls Sergeant Gordon your friend?
我不能有任何朋友
l don't have the luxury of friends.
我给你打镇定剂 你醒来后就会在你家
l'm gonna give you a sedative. You'll wake up back at home.
然后你要把这些交给戈登 千万不要相信别人
When you do, get these to Gordon, and Gordon alone. Trust no one.
- 这是什么? - 毒药的抗体
-What are they? -The antidote.
一瓶给戈登 另一瓶大量制造
One for Gordon to inoculate himself, the other for mass production.
大量制造?
Mass production?
克莱恩只是爪牙 我们要准备应战
Crane was just a pawn. We need to be ready.
当你说你想拯救高谭市
When you told me your grand plan for saving Gotham...
我没把你送进疯人院是因为...
...all that stopped me from calling the men in white coats...
你说你不是为了追求刺激
...was when you said it wasn't about thrill-seeking.
- 我并不是 - 那这算什么?
-lt's not. -What would you call that?
(高速公路大追击)
- 很精采的新闻 - 没有人受伤是个奇迹
-Damn good television. -lt's a miracle no one was killed.
我没时间遵守交通规则
l didn't have time to observe the rules of the road, Alfred.
你一手创造了一个怪物
You're getting lost inside this monster of yours.
我利用这个怪物帮助人们 就跟我父亲一样
l'm using this monster to help other people, just like my father did.
你父亲那么做
For Thomas Wayne, helping others...
不是为了证明给任何人看 包括他自己
...wasn't about proving anything to anyone, including himself.
我是为了瑞秋 她中了毒
lt's Rachel, Alfred. She was dying.
她就在楼下 请你送她回家
She's downstairs, sedated. l need you to take her home.
我们都很关心瑞秋 但你已失去控制
Well, we both care for Rachel, but what you're doing has to be beyond that.
为了徇私 就会变成恶徒
lt can't be personal, or you're just a vigilante.
- 福克斯还在吗? - 在
-ls Fox still here? -Yes, sir.
我们要把这些客人赶走
We need to send these people away.
你不能毁了布鲁斯韦恩的名誉
Those are Bruce Wayne's guests. You have a name to maintain.
我不在乎我的名誉
l don't care about my name.
不只是你 也是你父亲的名誉
lt's not just your name, sir. lt's your father's name.
他只留下他的名誉
And it's all that's left of him.
千万别毁了他的名誉
Don't destroy it.
- 厄尔先生 - 生日快乐
-Mr. Earle. -Happy birthday, Bruce.
谢谢你
Thank you.
公司的股价如何?
How did the stock offering go?
涨停板
Prices soared.
股票都是谁在买?
Who was buying?
基金和证券公司
All kinds of funds and brokerages.
你不会懂的
lt's a bit technical.
重点是
The key thing is...
- 公司的未来很稳定 - 那就好
...our company's future is secure. - Great.
她只是喝多了几杯
A little the worse for wear, l'm afraid.
你的计划是什么?
What was the plan, Crane?
你怎么把毒药释放在空气中?
How were you gonna get your toxin into the air?
稻草人 稻草人
Scarecrow. Scarecrow.
替谁工作?
Who were you working for, Crane?
太迟了
Oh, it's too late.
你阻止不了他
You can't stop it now.
拿去
Here.
- 生日快乐 布鲁斯 - 谢谢各位
-Happy birthday, Bruce. -Thank you. Thanks.
谢谢你的那样东西
And thank you for that item.
不客气
You're welcome.
- 我知道你会用来救人 - 我已经救了一个人
-l know you'll put it to good use. -l already have.
如果要大量制造要多久时间?
How long would it take to manufacture on a large scale?
几个星期 为什么问?
Weeks. Why?
有人想利用自来水散播毒素
Somebody's planning to disperse the toxin using the water supply.
自来水不能让人吸入毒素
The water supply won't help you disperse an inhalant.
什么?
What?
除非用微波发射器
Unless you have a microwave emitter powerful enough...
把水分蒸发
...to vaporize all the water in the mains.
就是韦恩企业弄丢的那一台
A microwave emitter like the one Wayne Enterprises just misplaced.
弄丢了?
Misplaced?
我多问几句就被厄尔开除
Earle just fired me for asking too many questions about it.
我要你回公司大量制造抗体
Go back to Wayne Enterprises now and start making more of that antidote.
警方会需要大量的抗体
The police are gonna need as much as they can get their hands on.
我公司的保全卡被没收了
My security clearance has been revoked.
你一定会有办法 对吧?
That wouldn't stop a man like you, would it?
我猜是吧
l suppose not.
- 布鲁斯 你一定要见一个人 - 我现在没空
-Bruce, there's somebody you must meet. -Not now, Mrs. Delane.
听听我念得对不对...
Now, am l pronouncing this right...
忍者大师?
...Mr. Ra's al Ghul?
你才不是忍者大师
You're not Ra's al Ghul.
我亲眼看到他死
l watched him die.
也许忍者大师不会死?
But is Ra's al Ghul immortal?
也许他有特异功能?
Are his methods supernatural?
也许你才是真正的忍者大师吧?
Or cheap parlor tricks to conceal your true identity, Ra's?
你自己在晚上化身为正义使者
Surely a man who spends his nights scrambling over the rooftops of Gotham...
应该不会怪我有双重身分吧?
...wouldn't begrudge me dual identities.
我救了你一命
l saved your life.
我教过你不能对敌人手下留情
l warned you about compassion, Bruce.
你要对付的是我
Your quarrel is with me.
放过这些人
You let these people go.
尽管去跟他们解释吧
You are welcome to explain the situation to them.
各位
Everyone.
各位来宾请听我说
Everybody?
我...
l....
要谢谢你们喝光我的酒
l want to thank you all for coming here tonight and drinking all of my booze.
我是说真的
No, really.
像我这种亿万大富翁
There's a thing about being a Wayne...
免不了会有很多人来白吃白喝
...that you're never short of a few freeloaders, like yourselves...
我敬大家 谢谢各位
...to fill up your mansion with. So here's to you people. Thank you.
- 够了 布鲁斯 - 我还没说完
-That's enough, Bruce. -l'm not finished.
你们这些...
To all of you....
你们这些伪君子 你们这些酒肉朋友
All of you phonies, all of you two-faced friends...
装一副笑脸 一心想讨好我
...you sycophantic suck-ups who smile through your teeth at me...
请你们别再来烦我
...please, leave me in peace.
请你们走吧
Please go.
我不是开玩笑 快走吧
Stop smiling, it's not a joke. Please leave.
派对结束了 快滚
The party's over, get out.
你丢尽了你父母的脸 韦恩先生
The apple has fallen very far from the tree, Mr. Wayne.
他真是越来越不像话
He's turning into a jerk.
很有意思
Amusing.
但是没有用 这些人都活不久了
But pointless. None of these people have long to live.
你对疗养院的注意 逼我不得不提早行动
Your antics at the asylum have forced my hand.
克莱恩果然是为你做事
So Crane was working for you.
他利用蓝花提炼毒药
His toxin is derived from the organic compound found in our blue flowers.
然后做成化学武器
He was able to weaponize it.
他不是影武者联盟成员?
He's not a member of the League of Shadows?
当然不是 他以为我们要勒索高谭市
Of course not. He thought our plan was to hold the city to ransom.
但是你其实要在高谭市下毒
But really, you are gonna release Crane's poison on the entire city.
然后看着市民因为恐惧自我毁灭
Then watch Gotham tear itself apart through fear.
你打算害死数百万条人命
You're gonna destroy millions of lives.
这些人活着也是痛苦
Only a cynical man would call what these people have ''lives,'' Wayne.
他们饱受犯罪荼毒
Crime. Despair.
活着还有什么意思呢?
This is not how man was supposed to live.
数千年来我们影武者联盟都在...
The League of Shadows has been a check against human corruption...
清除人间败类
...for thousands of years.
我们在古罗马制造瘟疫
We sacked Rome. Loaded trade ships with plague rats.
把伦敦夷为平地
Burned London to the ground.
每当人类文明腐败到极点
Every time a civilization reaches the pinnacle of its decadence...
我们就会将它毁灭
...we return to restore the balance.
高谭市还有得救
Gotham isn't beyond saving.
再给我时间 这里还有好人
Give me more time. There are good people here.
这个城市无药可救了 我们渗透了每一个阶层
You are defending a city so corrupt we have infiltrated every level of its infrastructure.
该出去玩了
Time to play.
我在牢里看到你时 你迷失了自我
When l found you in that jail, you were lost.
但是我相信你
But l believed in you.
我消除你的恐惧 指引你方向
l took away your fear, and l showed you a path.
你是我最好的徒弟
You were my greatest student.
你应该站在我身边拯救世界
lt should be you standing by my side, saving the world.
我要站在你面前
l'll be standing where l belong.
阻止你屠杀高谭市市民
Between you and the people of Gotham.
没有人救得了高谭市
No one can save Gotham.
当森林腐烂 野火会把它烧光
When a forest grows too wild, a purging fire is inevitable and natural.
明天是这座伟大城市的末日
Tomorrow the world will watch in horror as its greatest city destroys itself.
这次没有人能阻止我
The movement back to harmony will be unstoppable this time.
- 你曾经试过毁灭高谭市? - 当然了
-You attacked Gotham before? -Of course.
我们使用的方法越来越成熟
Over the ages our weapons have grown more sophisticated.
我们曾经造成经济大萧条
With Gotham we tried a new one. Economics.
但是我们低估了像你父母这种...
But we underestimated certain of Gotham's citizens...
善心人士的力量
...such as your parents.
结果他们竟被帮助的对象打死
Gunned down by one of the very people they were trying to help.
老百姓没饭吃被迫当强盗
Create enough hunger and everyone becomes a criminal.
你父母的死让高谭市民心连心
Their deaths galvanized the city into saving itself...
勉强撑到现在
...and Gotham has limped on ever since.
我们要来完成任务
We are back to finish the job.
这次不会有理想主义者碍事
And this time no misguided idealists will get in the way.
你跟你爸一样狠不下心
Like your father, you lack the courage to do all that is necessary.
如果有人敢阻止我们伸张正义
lf someone stands in the way of true justice...
我们就从背后捅他们一刀
...you simply walk up behind them and stab them in the heart.
- 我要阻止你的恶行 - 你学不会...
-l am gonna stop you. -You never did learn...
耳听四面、眼观八方
...to mind your surroundings.
正义就是有仇必报
Justice is balance.
你烧了我房子 差点害死我
You burned my house and left me for dead.
这下我们算扯平了
Consider us even.
确定没有人活着出来
No one comes out. Make sure.
他们都逃出去了?
They're all gone?
- 有多少重度病患逃出去? - 全部都逃出去
-How many from maximum security? -Every one of them.
连环杀手、强暴犯
Serial killers, rapists.
把桥梁升起 别让他们进城
Raise the bridges. We don't want any getting off the island.
好吧 就这么办
Yeah, l'll raise the bridges...
等支援警力来把那些神经病抓走
...when l get every available unit out here to catch the homicidal maniacs...
- 到时候再说吧 - 快去吧
-...that are running loose out there. -Come on!
希望你不是消防队员
l hope you're not a member of the fire brigade.
韦恩少爷!
Master Wayne! Master Wayne!
你成天健身连木头都抬不动?
What is the point of all those pushups if you can't even lift a bloody log?
我到底做了什么?
What have l done, Alfred?
韦恩宅邸...
Everything my family...
我父亲的心血...
...my father, built....
韦恩家族的精神不只是砖块瓦砾
The Wayne legacy is more than bricks and mortar, sir.
我想要拯救高谭市
l wanted to save Gotham.
我失败了
l failed.
我们为什么跌倒?
Why do we fall, sir?
这样才能学会站起来
So that we can learn to pick ourselves up.
你还是没放弃我 是吗?
You still haven't given up on me?
永远都不会
Never.
趴下来
Down!
警察暴力 警察动粗
Harassment! l see harassment!
你想看真正的警察暴力吗?
Maybe you'd like to see some excessive force?
拿了枪的疯子
Madman with a gun.
市民对警方镇压行动...
With residents furious at the unprecedented show of police strength...
感到愤怒
-...to round up the inmates....
我们要把桥梁升起来
We're about to raise these bridges.
我是检察官 让我过去
Officer, l am a Gotham City district attorney. Let me pass.
- 给我闭嘴! - 佛莱斯 别激动!
-Just shut up! -Hey, Flass, cool it!
冷静点
Hold these people back.
戈登 有人来找你
Hey, Gordon. Somebody here to see you.
- 你跑来干嘛? - 我们的朋友要我交给你
-What are you doing here? -Our friend sent me with this.
这是解药
lt counteracts Crane's toxin.
希望你用不着
Hopefully you won't need it.
除非有人把毒药释放在空气中
Not unless he's got some way of getting that crap into the air.
好了 不准过桥了
All right, last one across.
三分钟内就要把桥梁升起来
Come on, people, they want this bridge up in no more than three minutes!
你最好赶快离开这里
Better get you off the island before they raise the bridges. Patrolman!
快走吧
Go!
我找不到我妈妈
l can't find my mom.
喂!
Hey!
你想干什么?
What the hell are you doing?
各位
Gentlemen...
我们该行动了
...time to spread the word.
我们要引起一阵...
And the word is...
大恐慌
...panic.
(自来水厂)
水压突然上升
Jesus. The pressure, it's spiking.
就在那里
Right there.
那是奈何岛的地下水管
That water main is right under the Narrows.
没事了
lt's okay.
我是罗局长
This is Commissioner Loeb.
快向我报告
Come on, somebody talk to me.
说话啊!
Come on!
罗局长 我是戈登
Loeb, Loeb. This is Gordon.
到底发生什么事?
What the hell is going on?
我们需要支援 镇暴警察、霹雳小组
We need reinforcements. TAC teams, SWAT, riot cops!
戈登 镇暴警察都在你那里
Gordon! All the city's riot police are on the island with you!
他们都中了毒
Well, they're completely incapacitated!
没事了 没人会伤害你
lt's okay, it's okay. No one's gonna hurt you.
我就会伤害你
Of course they are!
- 克莱恩? - 不 我是稻草人
-Crane? -No. Scarecrow.
戈登
Gordon...
没有警力了
...there's nobody left to send in.
只剩下我一个人?
So l'm on my own?
奈何岛陷入一团混乱
The Narrows is tearing itself to pieces.
如果他们将毒药释放到全市
This is just the beginning. lf they hit the whole city...
就会引起高谭市的大恐慌
...there's nothing to stop Gotham tearing itself apart.
- 他们要怎么做? - 透过铁路系统
-How are they gonna do that? -The train.
自来水管沿着轨道到韦恩大楼底下
The monorail follows the water mains to the central hub beneath Wayne Tower.
只要在韦恩大楼发射微波
If the machine gets to the station...
就会把全市的供水蒸发
...it'll cause a chain reaction that'll vaporize the city's water supply.
让高谭市充满毒气
Covering Gotham in this poison.
我需要你帮我阻止他们
l'm gonna stop him from loading that train, but l may need your help.
- 你要我怎么做? - 你会开手排档吗?
-What do you need? -Can you drive stick?
你们在这里
There you are!
除了恐惧本身
There is nothing to fear...
没什么好怕的
...but fear itself!
我来帮你们...
l am here to help!
蝙蝠侠会来救我们
Batman will save us. He'll come.
- 他一定会来 - 不要看
-He'll come. -Don't peek.
我是戈登 把桥放下来
This is Gordon. Prepare to lower the bridge.
我就说他一定会来
l told you he'd come.
等等
Wait.
你很可能没命
You could die.
至少告诉我你是谁
At least tell me your name.
我在外表底下是谁并不重要
lt's not who l am underneath...
我的所作所为才重要
...but what l do that defines me.
布鲁斯?
Bruce?
你真的听我的话 扮成一个怪物
Well, well. You took my advice about theatricality a bit literally.
- 你的恶行到此为止 - 你跟警察才到此为止
-lt ends here. -For you and the police, maybe.
我要对付的是整个高谭市
My fight, however, lies with the rest of Gotham.
恕我失陪 我要摧毁这座城市
Now, if you'll excuse me, l have a city to destroy.
- 你以为我打不过他们? - 请便吧
-l can't beat two of your pawns? -As you wish.
全球定位系统连线
GPS online.
距离一百码
In 1 00 yards.
上吧
Gentlemen.
谁下令把桥放下来?
Who the hell authorized this?
距离韦恩大楼三英里
Distance to Wayne Tower, three miles.
水压把沿路的水管炸爆
The pressure's moving along the mains, blowing the pipes.
如果波及自来水厂
lf that pressure reaches us...
全市的自来水管都会爆炸
...the water supply right across the whole city is gonna blow!
在下一个街口右转
At the next intersection, turn right.
你永远都学不会
You will never learn.
不好意思
Sorry.
- 你没有新的招式吗? - 这一招怎么样?
-Familiar. Don't you have anything new? -How about this?!
您已抵达目的地 韦恩大楼
You have arrived at Wayne Tower.
快疏散整座大楼
Evacuate the building.
楼下的自来水厂会爆炸
We're on top of the main hub and it's gonna blow.
启动武器系统
Weapons system activated.
好厉害的车
Nice ride.
准备攻击
Armed.
(水压过高)
不要怕 布鲁斯
Don't be afraid, Bruce.
来吧 来吧
Come on. Come on.
你只是穿着披风的凡人
You are just an ordinary man in a cape.
不能伸张正义 不能阻止列车
That's why you couldn't fight injustice, that's why you can't stop this train.
谁说我要阻止列车?
Who said anything about stopping it?
太帅了
Yes!
你学不会耳听四面、眼观八方
You never learned to mind your surroundings!
你终于学会狠下心来了?
Have you finally learned to do what is necessary?
我不会杀你
l won't kill you...
但是我也不必救你
...but l don't have to save you.
- 会议已经开始了 - 什么会议?
-The meeting's already started. -What meeting?
福克斯 我炒了你鱿鱼
Fox, l seem to remember firing you.
没错
You did.
我找到新工作
l got another job.
你的工作
Yours.
谁有这个权力?
On whose authority?
蝙蝠侠上了头版新闻
Batman may have made the front page...
布鲁斯韦恩只上了第八版
...but Bruce Wayne got pushed to page eight.
(酒醉亿万富翁烧毁豪宅)
我是布鲁斯韦恩
Bruce Wayne.
你凭什么决定谁来掌管公司?
What makes you think you can decide who's running Wayne Enterprises?
- 因为我是公司老板 - 你在说什么?
-The fact that l'm the owner. -What are you talking about?
公司一星期前上市
The company went public a week ago.
我透过各种基金...
And l bought most of the shares.
买下大半股权
Through various charitable foundations and trusts and so forth.
你不会懂的 重点是...
Look, it's all a bit technical, but the important thing...
我的公司的未来很稳定
...is that my company's future is secure.
对吧 福克斯先生?
Right, Mr. Fox?
一点也没错
Right you are, Mr. Wayne.
你没收到通知吗?
Didn't you get the memo?
- 很抱歉我没告诉你 - 不必道歉
-l'm sorry l didn't tell you, Rachel. -No. No, Bruce...
不 我才要道歉
...l'm sorry.
齐利被枪杀那天
The day that Chill died, l....
我对你说了重话
l said terrible things.
那也是真话
But true things.
我当时是个懦夫
l was a coward with a gun...
正义不代表报仇 我要谢谢你
...and justice is about more than revenge, so thank you.
我一直在想着你
l never stopped thinking about you.
还有我们
About us.
我听说你回来
And when l heard you were back, l....
我就抱着希望
l started to hope.
但是后来我发现你的面具
But then l found out about your mask.
蝙蝠侠只是我的化身
Batman's just a symbol, Rachel.
不
No. This...
这是你的面具
...is your mask.
现在的你是犯罪克星
Your real face is the one that criminals now fear.
我深爱的人
The man l loved...
曾经离开我的人
...the man who vanished...
他根本就没有回来
...he never came back at all.
他还在世界某个角落
But maybe he's still out there somewhere.
有一天高谭市不再需要蝙蝠侠
Maybe someday, when Gotham no longer needs Batman...
也许我会再见到他
...l'll see him again.
- 你证明我错了 - 什么事?
-Proved me wrong, you know. -About what?
你父亲会以你为荣
Your father would be very proud of you.
就像我一样
Just like me.
你接下来有什么打算?
What will you do?
重新开始
Rebuild it.
一砖一瓦重建家园
Just the way it was, brick for brick.
就跟以前一样吗?
Just the way it was, sir?
是啊 怎么样?
Yeah, why?
我觉得可以
l thought this might be a good opportunity for...
加强地基的部分
...improving the foundations.
- 东南角的地基吗? - 没错
-ln the southeast corner? -Precisely, sir.
- 挺好的 - 我找不到黑帮老大绑在上面
-Nice. -l couldn't find any mob bosses.
- 警官 - 我现在是队长了
-Well, sergeant? -lt's ''lieutenant'' now.
你改变了现状
You really started something.
坏警察不敢再乱来
Bent cops running scared.
人们也充满希望
Hope on the streets.
- 但是呢? - 奈何岛仍然被罪犯控制
-But? -The Narrows is lost.
克莱恩和变态恶徒也没落网
And we still haven't picked up Crane or half the inmates of Arkham that he freed.
我们会抓到他们的
We will.
我们可以拯救高谭市
We can bring Gotham back.
- 道高一尺、魔高一丈? - 怎么说?
-What about escalation? -Escalation?
警察开始用半自动步枪 歹徒就买自动步枪
We start carrying semiautomatics, they buy automatics.
我们穿防弹衣 他们用达姆弹
We start wearing Kevlar, they buy armor-piercing rounds.
- 然后呢? - 你戴着面具
-And? -And you're wearing a mask...
飞檐走壁
...and jumping off rooftops.
就拿这家伙来说
Now, take this guy.
杀人放火、无恶不作
Armed robbery, double homicide.
他跟你一样爱玩变装秀
Got a taste for the theatrical, like you.
犯案后都留下名片
Leaves a calling card.
(小丑)
我会查查他的底细
l'll look into it.
我一直没谢谢你
l never said thank you.
你也永远不用谢我
And you'll never have to.